Phone: (215) 990-7036

Citizenship: USA

CONTACT Information Fermi National Accelerator Laboratory

 ${\it Theoretical~Physics~Division,~Astrophysics~Department}$

Website: https://samueldmcdermott.github.io/

Email: samueldmcdermott@gmail.com

AREAS OF EXPERTISE General: High-dimensional Bayesian parameter inference and uncertainty quantification; machine learning (97.25% in Andrew Ng's Coursera class, member of Deep Skies Lab at KICP and FNAL); 1D and 2D signal analysis; wavelet transforms.

Academic: Identification of particle physics beyond the Standard Model; maximizing utility of astrophysical data sets; new physics in stars, extreme astrophysical environments, and cosmological settings.

EMPLOYMENT

Fermi National Accelerator Laboratory

Sept 2017 / Jan 2019 - Sept 2022

Postdoctoral associate / Schramm Fellow

C. N. Yang Institute for Theoretical Physics

Sept 2014 - Sept 2017

Postdoctoral Associate

EDUCATION

Ph.D., Physics, The University of Michigan, Ann Arbor

Aug 2014

Dissertation Advisor: Dr. Kathryn M. Zurek

B.A., Physics and **B.A.**, Math, The University of Pennsylvania

Dec 2008

Research Advisor: Dr. Marija Drndic

AWARDS AND RECOGNITION Fermilab

• Schramm Fellowship

2019

• URA Thesis Award

2015

• Predoctoral Theory Fellowship

2013-2014

The University of Michigan

• Rackham Predoctoral Fellowship

2013-2014

The University of Pennsylvania

• Summa cum Laude, with Distinction in Physics; Dean's List, all semesters; Benjamin Franklin Scholar; Phi Beta Kappa scholar

Publication Statistics According to the **inSpireHEP** database, as of September 2, 2022:

- 47 research publications and 1 review article
- 9 Letters published (7 in the Physical Review, 1 in the Astrophysical Journal, 1 in Physics Letters B)
- one solicited whitepaper for Snowmass 2020; numerous letters of interest for Snowmass 2020 and Astro20 Decadal
- more than 3,850 total citations
- h-index: 28

PUBLICATIONS

Prepared while at Fermilab as a postdoctoral associate:

48. SDM, Yi-Ming Zhong, and Ilias Cholis. A Phantom Menace: On the Morphology of the Galactic Center Excess. arXiv:2209.00006. FERMILAB-PUB-22-650-T.

- 47. Jeremy Sakstein, Djuna Croon, and SDM. Axion Instability Supernovae. Phys. Rev. D **105**, 095038 (2022). arXiv:2203.06160. FERMILAB-PUB-22-118-T.
- 46. Ilias Cholis, Yi-Ming Zhong, SDM, and Joseph P. Surdutovich. The Return of the Templates: Revisiting the Galactic Center Excess with Multi-Messenger Observations. Phys. Rev. D 105, no.10, 103023 (2022). arXiv:2112.09706 [astro-ph]. FERMILAB-PUB-21-709-T.
- 45. Marcela Carena, Nina M. Coyle, Yingying Li, SDM, and Yuhsin Tsai. *Cosmologically Degenerate Fermions*. arXiv:2108.02785. FERMILAB-PUB-21-325-T.
- 44. Susan Gardner, SDM, and Brian Yanny. The Milky Way, Coming into Focus: Precision Astrometry Probes its Evolution, and its Dark Matter. Prog. Part. Nucl. Phys. 121, 103904 (2021). arXiv:2106.13284 [astro-ph]. FERMILAB-PUB-21-297-T.
- 43. Pierce Giffin, John Lloyd, SDM, and Stefano Profumo. Neutron Star Quantum Death by Small Black Holes. Phys. Rev. D **105**, 123030 (2022). arXiv:2105.06504. FERMILAB-PUB-21-259-T.
- 42. Eric J. Baxter, Djuna Croon, SDM, and Jeremy Sakstein. Find the Gap: Black Hole Population Analysis with an Astrophysically Motivated Mass Function. Astrophys. J. Lett. **916**, no.2, L16 (2021). arXiv:2104.02685 [astro-ph]. FERMILAB-PUB-21-148-T.
- 41. Carlos Blanco, Yonatan Kahn, Benjamin Lillard, and SDM, Dark Matter Daily Modulation With Anisotropic Organic Crystals. Phys. Rev. D **104**, 036011 (2021). arXiv:2103.08601. FERMILAB-PUB-21-066-T.
- 40. James M. Cline, Guillermo Gambini, SDM, and Matteo Puel, *Late-Time Dark Matter Oscillations and the Core-Cusp Problem*. JHEP **04**, 223 (2021). arXiv:2010.12583. FERMILAB-PUB-20-556-T.
- 39. Jeremy Sakstein, Djuna Croon, SDM, Maria C. Straight and Eric J. Baxter, Beyond the Standard Model Explanations of GW190521. Phys. Rev. Lett. 125, no.26, 261105 (2020). arXiv:2009.01213 [gr-qc]. FERMILAB-PUB-20-461-T.
- 38. Djuna Croon, SDM, and Jeremy Sakstein. *Missing in Action: New Physics and the Black Hole Mass Gap.* Phys. Rev. D **102**, no. 11, 115024; selected as an **Editor's Choice** article. arXiv:2007.07889 [gr-qc]. FERMILAB-PUB-20-328-T.
- 37. Djuna Croon, SDM, and Jeremy Sakstein. *Missing in Axion: where are XENON1T's big black holes?* Phys. Dark Univ. **32**, 100801 (2021). arXiv:2007.00650. FERMILAB-PUB-20-270-T.
- 36. Djuna Croon, Gilly Elor, Rebecca Leane, and SDM. Supernova Muons: New Constraints on Z' Bosons, Axions, and ALPs. JHEP **01**, 107 (2021). arXiv:2006.13942. FERMILAB-PUB-20-246-A-T.
- 35. Celeste Keith, Dan Hooper, SDM, and Nikita Blinov. Constraints on Primordial Black Holes From Big Bang Nucleosynthesis Revisited. Phys. Rev. D **102**, no.10, 103512 (2020). arXiv:2006.03608 [astro-ph]. FERMILAB-PUB-20-224-A.

- 34. Dan Hooper, Gordan Krnjaic, John March-Russell, SDM, and Rudin Petrossian-Byrne. *Hot Gravitons and Gravitational Waves From Kerr Black Holes in the Early Universe*. arXiv:2004.00618 [astro-ph]. FERMILAB-PUB-20-125-A-T.
- 33. Samuel J. Witte, Salvador Rosauro-Alcaraz, SDM, and Vivian Poulin. *Dark Photon Dark Matter in the Presence of Inhomogeneous Structure*. JHEP **06**, 132 (2020). arXiv:2003.13698 [astro-ph]. FERMILAB-PUB-20-121-T.
- 32. Yi-Ming Zhong, SDM, Ilias Cholis, and Patrick J. Fox. A New Mask for An Old Suspect: Testing the Sensitivity of the Galactic Center Excess to the Point Source Mask. Phys. Rev. Lett. **124**, no.23, 231103 (2020). arXiv:1911.12369 [astro-ph]. FERMILAB-PUB-19-575-T.
- 31. SDM and Samuel J. Witte. *The Cosmological Evolution of Light Dark Photon Dark Matter*. Phys. Rev. D **101**, 063030 (2020). arXiv:1911.05086 [hep-ph]. FERMILAB-PUB-19-565-T.
- 30. Gordan Krnjaic and SDM. Implications of BBN Bounds for Cosmic Ray Upscattered Dark Matter. Phys. Rev. D **101**, no.12, 123022 (2020). arXiv:1908.00007 [hep-ph]. FERMILAB-PUB-19-358-A.
- 29. Nikita Blinov, Kevin J. Kelly, Gordan Krnjaic, and SDM. Constraining the Self-Interacting Neutrino Interpretation of the Hubble Tension. Phys. Rev. Lett. 123, no. 19, 191102 (2019). arXiv:1905.02727 [astro-ph]. FERMILAB-PUB-19-175-A-T.
- 28. Dan Hooper, Gordan Krnjaic, and SDM. Dark Radiation and Superheavy Dark Matter from Black Hole Domination. JHEP **08**, 001 (2019). arXiv:1905.01301 [hep-ph]. FERMILAB-PUB-19-186-A.
- 27. SDM and Michael S. Turner. Nuclear Kinetic Equilibrium During Big Bang Nucleosynthesis. arXiv:1811.04932 [hep-ph]. FERMILAB-PUB-18-625-A
- 26. SDM, Sanjay Reddy, and Srimoyee Sen. A Deeply Bound Dibaryon is Incompatible with Neutron Stars and Supernovae. Phys. Rev. D **99**, no. 3, 035013 (2019). arXiv:1809.06765 [hep-ph]. FERMILAB-PUB-18-490-A.
- 25. Rouven Essig, SDM, Hai-Bo Yu, and Yi-Ming Zhong. *Constraining Dissipative Dark Matter Self-Interactions*. Phys. Rev. Lett. **123**, no. 12, 121102 (2019). arXiv:1809.01144 [hep-ph]. FERMILAB-PUB-18-437-A.
- 24. Dan Hooper, Gordan Krnjaic, Andrew J. Long, and SDM. WIMPflation. Phys. Rev. Lett. **122**, no. 9, 091802 (2019). arXiv:1807.03308 [hep-ph]. FERMILAB-PUB-18-309-A.
- 23. Asher Berlin, Dan Hooper, Gordan Krnjaic, and SDM. Severely Constraining Dark Matter Interpretations of the 21-cm Anomaly. Phys. Rev. Lett. 121, no. 1, 011102 (2018); selected as an Editor's Choice article. arXiv:1803.02804 [hep-ph]. FERMILAB-PUB-18-066-A.
- 22. Bhaskaran Balaji, Ilias Cholis, Patrick J. Fox, and SDM. *Analyzing the Gamma-ray Sky with Wavelets*. arXiv:1803.01952 [astro-ph]. Phys. Rev. D **98**, no. 4, 043009 (2018). FERMILAB-PUB-18-057-A-T.

- 21. Jae Hyeok Chang, Rouven Essig, and SDM. Supernova 1987A Constraints on Sub-GeV Dark Sectors, Millicharged Particles, the QCD Axion, and an Axion-like Particle. JHEP **09**, 051 (2018). arXiv:1803.00993 [hep-ph]. YITP-SB-18-01, FERMILAB-PUB-17-432-T.
- 20. Dan Hooper and SDM. Robust Constraints and Novel Gamma-Ray Signatures of Dark Matter That Interacts Strongly With Nucleons. Phys. Rev. D 97, 115006 (2018). arXiv:1802.03025 [hep-ph]. FERMILAB-PUB-18-032-A.
- 19. SDM. Is Self-Interacting Dark Matter Undergoing Dark Fusion? Phys. Rev. Lett. 120, 221806 (2018); selected as an Editor's Choice article. arXiv:1711.00857 [hep-ph]. FERMILAB-PUB-17-483-A-T.

Prepared while at YITP Stony Brook as a postdoctoral associate:

- 18. SDM, Hiren H. Patel, and Harikrishnan Ramani. Dark Photon Decay Beyond The Euler-Heisenberg Limit. Phys. Rev. D **97**, no. 7, 073005 (2018). arXiv:1705.00619 [hep-ph]. YITP-SB-17-14.
- 17. Samuel Witte, Vera Gluscevic, and SDM. Prospects for Distinguishing Dark Matter Models Using Annual Modulation. JCAP **02**, no. 02, 044 (2017). arXiv:1612.07808 [hep-ph]. YITP-SB-16-51.
- 16. Jae Hyeok Chang, Rouven Essig, and SDM. Revisiting Supernova 1987A Bounds on Dark Photons. JHEP **01**, 107 (2017). arXiv:1611.03864 [hep-ph]. YITP-SB-16-44.
- 15. SDM, Patrick Meade, and Harikrishnan Ramani. Singlet Scalar Resonances and the Diphoton Excess. Phys. Lett. B **755**, 353 (2016). arXiv:1512.05326 [hep-ph]. YITP-SB-15-47.
- 14. SDM, Ilias Cholis, Patrick J. Fox, and Samuel K. Lee. Wavelet-Based Techniques for the Gamma-Ray Sky. JCAP **07**, 07, 045, (2016). arXiv:1512.00012 [astro-ph]. YITP-SB-15-43.
- 13. Asher Berlin, Dan Hooper, and SDM. Dark matter elastic scattering through Higgs loops. Phys. Rev. D **92**, no. 12, 123531 (2015). arXiv:1508.05390 [hep-ph]. YITP-SB-15-29.
- 12. Hooman Davoudiasl, Dan Hooper, and SDM. *Inflatable Dark Matter*. Phys. Rev. Lett. **116**, 031303 (2016); selected as an **Editor's Choice** article. arXiv:1507.08660 [hep-ph]. YITP-SB-15-26.
- 11. Vera Gluscevic, Moira Gresham, SDM, Annika H. G. Peter, and Kathryn M. Zurek. *Identifying the Theory of Dark Matter with Direct Detection*. JCAP **12**, 12, 057 (2015). arXiv:1506.04454 [hep-ph]. YITP-SB-15-16. Associated code publicly available on github and ASCL.

Prepared while at Fermilab as a Fermilab Fellow:

- 10. SDM. Lining up the Galactic Center Gamma-Ray Excess. Phys. Dark Univ. 7-8, 12 (2015). arXiv:1406.6408 [hep-ph]. FERMILAB-PUB-14-205-A-T.
- 9. Asher Berlin, Pierre Gratia, Dan Hooper, and SDM. *Hidden Sector Dark Matter Models for the Galactic Center Gamma-Ray Excess*. Phys. Rev. D **90**, 015032 (2014). arXiv:1405.5204 [hep-ph]. MCTP-14-12, FERMILAB-PUB-14-134-A.

- 8. Asher Berlin, Dan Hooper, and SDM. Simplified Dark Matter Models for the Galactic Center Gamma-Ray Excess. Phys. Rev. D 89, 115022 (2014). arXiv:1404.0022 [hep-ph]. MCTP-14-07, FERMILAB-PUB-14-060-A.
- 7. Ilias Cholis, Dan Hooper, and SDM. Dissecting the Gamma-Ray Background in Search of Dark Matter. JCAP **02**, 014 (2014). arXiv:1312.0608 [astro-ph]. MCTP-13-40, FERMILAB-PUB-13-546-A.
- Rouven Essig, Eric Kuflik, SDM, Tomer Volansky, and Kathryn M. Zurek. Constraining Light Dark Matter with Diffuse X-Ray and Gamma-Ray Observations.
 JHEP 11, 193 (2013). arXiv:1309.4091 [hep-ph]. MCTP-13-27, FERMILAB-PUB-13-377-A-T.

Prepared while a graduate student at the University of Michigan and a member of the Michigan Center for Theoretical Physics (MCTP):

- 5. Clifford Cheung, SDM, and Kathryn M. Zurek. *Inspecting the Higgs for New Weakly Interacting Particles*. JHEP **04**, 074 (2013). arXiv:1302.0314 [hep-ph]. MCTP-13-01.
- 4. Eric Kuflik, SDM, and Kathryn M. Zurek. Neutrino Phenomenology in a 3+1+1 Framework. Phys. Rev. D 86, 033015 (2012). arXiv:1205.1791 [hep-ph]. MCTP-12-11.
- 3. SDM, Hai-Bo Yu, and Kathryn M. Zurek. *The Dark Matter Inverse Problem: Extracting Particle Physics from Scattering Events*. Phys. Rev. D **85**, 123507 (2012). arXiv:1110.4281 [hep-ph]. MCTP-11-34.
- 2. SDM, Hai-Bo Yu, and Kathryn M. Zurek. Constraints on Scalar Asymmetric Dark Matter from Black Hole Formation in Neutron Stars. Phys. Rev. D 85, 023519 (2012). arXiv:1103.5472 [hep-ph]. MCTP-11-16.
- 1. SDM, Hai-Bo Yu, and Kathryn M. Zurek. Turning off the Lights: How Dark is Dark Matter? Phys. Rev. D 83, 063509 (2011). arXiv:1011.2907 [hep-ph]. MCTP-10-52.

Code

I have the following programming language skills

- Proficiency: Python (numpy, scipy, keras, jax, numpyro, ...), Mathematica, HTML
- Familiarity: Cython, CSS, bash, slurm

In addition, I wrote the following code packages:

- gcepy is a code for sampling for testing models of the Galactic center excess (GCE). This code relies on jax for all basic definitions, building up to a log-likelihood for the model given the data. The repository provides an ipynb demonstrating how to use two high-dimensional samplers, dynesty and numpyro, to derive constraints on the parameters.
- dmdd, ascl:1506.002, is a python package that enables simple simulation and Bayesian posterior analysis of nuclear-recoil data from dark matter direct detection experiments for a wide variety of theories of dark matter-nucleon interactions. dmdd was developed in collaboration with Vera Gluscevic for use in arXiv:1506.04454, additionally with Moira Gresham, Annika H. G. Peter, and Kathryn M. Zurek. dmdd was used by the PICO collaboration to set official limits in arXiv:1510.07754 [hep-ex]

Colloquia and	New Physics at the Stellar Frontier	
SUMMARY TALKS	 Argonne National Laboratory Physics Division 	Jan 27, 2022
	• University of Utah Department of Physics & Astronomy	Jan 25, 2022
	• King's College London Theoretical Particle Physics & Cosmology	Oct 25, 2021
	Stellar Probes of New Physics Topical Review	
	• Brookhaven Forum 2021	Nov 3, 2021
	Hunting for Dark Matter in the Lab, the Galaxy, and the Universe	
	• University of Victoria Department of Physics & Astronomy	Mar 9, 2020
Invited Talks	Agganted tening.	
	Assorted topics: Cornection Mellon University: Steller Tests of Crevity: Workshop	Man 19 2022
(*REMOTE)	Carnegie Mellon University Stellar Tests of Gravity Workshop Description University of California Barbalay	Mar 18 2022
	4D Seminar, University of California Berkeley *Carleton HED Seminar	Feb 14, 2022
	*Carleton HEP Seminar *INT Workshop	Nov 8, 2021
	*INT Workshop*BSM PANDEMIC Series	Sept 21, 2021
		Sept 14, 2021
	• *Particles and Nuclei International Conference	Sept 8, 2021
	• *Cambridge (Mass.) High Energy Workshop 2021 - Axion Physics	July 28, 2021
	• *APS DPF 2021	July 13, 2021
	• *The 16th Marcel Grossman Meeting	July 8, 2021
	• *Cosmology from Home	July 7, 2021
	• *A Rainbow of Dark Sectors, Aspen Center for Physics	Apr 1, 2021
	• *HEP Seminar, UC Santa Barbara	Nov 16, 2020
	• *APEC Seminar, Kavli IPMU	Oct 21, 2020
	*SITP Seminar, Stanford University	Oct 15, 2020
	• *High Energy Theory Seminar, Brown University	Oct 14, 2020
	• *High Energy Physics Seminar, Caltech	Oct 12, 2020
	• *Perimeter Institute Seminar	Apr $28, 2020$
	• *MCFP Seminar, University of Maryland	Mar 26, 2020
	• *Theory Seminar, Notre Dame	Feb 23, 2020
	• *N3AS Seminar	Feb $2, 2020$
	• *Israeli Joint Particle Physics Seminar, Hebrew University	Jun 24, 2020
	• *Thursday Seminar, CERN Th	Mar 19, 2020
	 New Techniques for Dark Matter Discovery, TRIUMF 	Mar 12, 2020
	• CCPP Seminar, New York University	Jan 31, 2020
	 YITP-Brookhaven Joint Seminar, Stony Brook University 	Jan 29, 2020
	• Informal Seminar, Harvard University	Jan 24, 2020
	 Nuclear Theory Seminar, University of Kentucky 	Dec 19, 2019
	• Nuclear and Particle Theory Seminar, MIT	Oct 28, 2019
	• Exceptional Seminar, CERN Th	Sept 30, 2019
	• CCPP Seminar, New York University	Feb 9, 2019
	• Brown Bag Seminar, University of Michigan	Oct 31, 2018
	• Cosmic Controversies, KICP	Oct 7, 2019
	• No Stone Unturned Workshop, Utah	Aug 7, 2019
	• Current Trends in Particle Theory, UIC	June 16, 2019
	• AAS Dark Matter "Meeting within a Meeting"	June 11, 2019
	• LSST Dark Matter Workshop, KICP	Aug 5, 2019
	• multiple, Aspen Center for Physics 2015, 2016,	2017, and 2019
	• Seventh PIMKIO meeting, University of Michigan	March 29, 2019

• Theory Seminar, Argonne National Lab	April 9, 2019
• Twelfth Conference on the Identification of Dark Matter	July 23, 2018
• CIPANP XIII	May 30 and 31, 2018
• Theoretical Astrophysics Seminar, Fermilab	May 21, 2018
• Kavli Institute for Theoretical Physics	Apr 10, 2018
• Theoretical Physics Seminar, Brandeis University	Feb 15, 2018
• Theoretical Astrophysics Seminar, Fermilab	Feb 5, 2018
• Particle Theory Seminar, Perimeter Institute	$\mathrm{Dec}\ 1,\ 2017$
• HPS Collaboration Telecon	Nov 15, 2017
• Particle Physics Seminar, University of Washington	Oct 24, 2017
• ITS Seminar, University of Oregon	Oct 23, 2017
• Theory Seminar, SLAC	Oct 20, 2017
• 4D Seminar, Berkeley	Oct 18, 2017
• Particle Theory Seminar, Boston University	Oct 11, 2017
• CFP Seminar, University of Maryland	Apr $10, 2017$
• Nuclear Theory Seminar, University of Kentucky	Apr $6, 2017$
• High Energy Theory Seminar, University of Minnesota	Mar 10, 2017
• HEP Seminar, Johns Hopkins University	Oct 25, 2016
• Dark Interactions Workshop, Brookhaven	Sep 7, 2016
• Joint Particle Seminar, UC Irvine	Apr 27, 2016
• High Energy Physics Seminar, Caltech	Apr 25, 2016
• Astro Coffee, IAS	Feb 3, 2016
• Pheno & Vino, Princeton	Feb 2, 2016
Galileo Galilei Institute workshop	Sep 30, 2015
• APS DPF meeting, Ann Arbor	Aug 5, 2015
• URA Thesis Award Presentation, Fermilab Users Meeting	June 10, 2015
Cornell Particle Theory Seminar	Apr 10, 2015
Maryland CFP	Mar 9, 2015
Brookhaven National Lab	Mar 4, 2015
• UT Austin Theory Group Seminar	Nov 4, 2014
• IAS Astro Coffee	Oct 8, 2014
• MIT CTP	Oct 1, 2014
• Université de Montréal and McGill dark matter workshop	July 24, 2014
• University of Chicago Dark Matter Hub meeting	Apr 15, 2014
• Los Alamos T2 Seminar	Dec 5, 2013
Wisconsin Theory Seminar	Nov 8, 2013
• SLAC Theoretical Physics Seminar	Oct 30, 2013
• Fermilab Theory Seminar	Oct 17, 2013
In addition I have given parallel and other talks at the Mid	· ·

In addition, I have given parallel and other talks at the Midwest Relativity Meeting, FNAL, Brookhaven Forum, YITP, COSMO2014, TeVPA/IDM 2014, the Pitt Phenomenology meetings, and the 19th SUSY meeting

Professional Service

Referee: Phys. Rev. Letters, the Astrophysical Journal, MNRAS Letters, JHEP, Phys. Rev. D, and Phys. Letters B.

Organizer of the following conferences, workshops, and meetings:

• Dark Matter in Compact Objects, Stars, and in Low Energy Experiments (22-2b) (Aug 1- Sep 2, 2022) at the University of Washington's Institute for Nuclear Theory;

inclusive of a \$106,400 grant from the Institute for Nuclear Theory

- Next Frontiers in the Search for Dark Matter (Aug 26 Oct 11, 2019) at Galileo Galilei Institute in Arcetri, Italy; inclusive of a five-day conference
- New Directions in the Search for Light Dark Matter Particles (June 4-7, 2019) at Fermilab and KICP; awarded \$24,525 grant from the Gordon and Betty Moore Foundation
- Beyond WIMPs: from Theory to Detection (March 27-29, 2017) at the Simons Center for Geometry and Physics
- Light Dark Matter: Asymmetric, thermal and non-thermal dark matter and its detection (April, 2013) at the Michigan Center for Theoretical Physics

Press

Hershberger, Scott. "Physics at Tiniest Scale Could Explain 'Impossible' Black Holes" Symmetry Magazine, 16 December 2020.

Hershberger, Scott. "If Betelgeuse goes boom: How DUNE would respond to a nearby supernova." Fermilab News, 5 October 2020.

Sakstein, Jeremy and Croon, Djuna, and SDM. "Beyond the Standard Model Explanations of GW190521." Newsletter of the CERN Experimental Physics Department, 29 September 2020.

Hekkenberg, Ans. "Overschot straling centrum Melkweg niet te verklaren met donkere materie" (Dutch) newscientist.nl, 8 September 2020.

Fadelli, Ingrid. "Could recently spotted dim point sources explain the galactic center excess (GCE)?" *Phys.orq*, 14 July 2020.

Muñoz, Julian and Loeb, Abraham. "The First Stars May Shed Light on Dark Matter." *APS Physics*, 2 July 2018.

Conover, Emily. "If real, dark fusion could help demystify this physics puzzle." *Science News*, 6 June 2018.

Inglis-Arkell, Esther. "'Inflatable Dark Matter' Could Explain Why We See Less Than Many Theories Predict." *Gizmodo*, 18 January 2016.